《ナルト：今のうちだ！》
This is my chance!
クッソー　やっぱ　速ぇ！
Damn it!
No doubt! He's fast!
（エー）フンッ！
《けど　もう１回！》
But…I'll try one more time!
（カツユ）速すぎて目で追えません。
He's so fast, I can't track them!
お前のラリアットで
わしに勝てると思っているのか！
Do you think you can beat me
with your Lariat?!
ビーのおっちゃん！
Octopops!
他人の心配などしてる暇が…。
If you have time to worry
about someone, worry about…
どうしてだ？　ビー。
Why, Bee?!
（ビー）まだわからねえのか　ブラザー
バカ野郎　この野郎！
Don't you get it yet, Bro?
Fool, ya fool!
ありがとう　ビーのおっちゃん！
Thanks, Octopops!
《これで雷影のおっちゃんを
突破できる》
Now I can get away from
the Raikage…
No!
火影　キサマも手伝え！
Hokage! You help too!
綱手様…。
Lady Tsunade…
《諦めねえ》
I'm not giving up…
((綱手：私をかばうな！
ナルト　もうやめろ！
Don't try to protect me!
Naruto, stop!
死んだら何もかも
夢も何もないんだよ！
If you die, your dreams,
everything will be gone!
フンッ　大丈夫だってばよ！
I'm all right.
もういいから　どけ！　逃げろ！
Enough! Move! And run!
俺は火影になるまで→
Until I become Hokage,
there's no way…
(ぜってぇ　死なねえからよ！))
I'm gonna die.
バ　バアちゃん！
Granny!
火影　キサマ　出来のいい言い訳は
できてるんだろうな？
Hokage!
You'd better have
a good excuse for this!
Two Suns
Hokage!
火影　キサマ　出来のいい言い訳は
できてるんだろうな？
You'd better have
a good excuse for this!
もし　ここでナルトを殺し→
Even if you kill Naruto to
buy us some time
九尾復活までの時間を
のばしたとしても→
until the Nine Tails comes back to life,
I can't see the next Jinchuriki
managing to control
次の人柱力が　ここまで九尾の力を
コントロールできるとは思えん！
the Nine Tail's power,
to this degree!
どうせ　どっちに転ぶか
わからぬ戦争なら→
Since we have no idea
which way this war will go,
I say we use
all the weapons we've got,
力いっぱい
出し惜しみなしでやるべきだ。
and not keep
the Jinchuriki in hiding!
私はナルトを行かせる！
I will let Naruto pass!
Nice excuse!
ナイス言い訳！
って　言い訳じゃねえけど。
I mean, now you're talking!
それでこそ　俺の知ってる
火影のバアちゃんだってばよ。
That's the Granny Hokage I know!
火影　キサマこそ
勝手な自己判断じゃないのか？
Hokage… Who's the one making
arbitrary decisions now?!
Each one of you…
どいつもこいつも→
What evidence do you have
that Naruto will succeed?!
なぜナルトが
やれるという保証がある。
I already told you that
a Lariat like yours won't work!
お前ごときのラリアットは
効かんと言ったはずだ。
Bro, ever since you became
the Raikage,
ブラザー　雷影になってから→
you've underestimated my power,
fool, ya fool!
俺の力を見誤ってるぜ
バカ野郎　この野郎！
((まさか　三代目雷影様が
お亡くなりになろうとは…。
No one ever expected
the Third Raikage to die…
ブラザーは　どっち　あっち？　こっち？
Where's Bro?
Over there? Over here?
いきなり壁を殴り崩して
外へ出ていきおった。
All of a sudden,
he started punching
his way out through the wall.
おそらく　いくつも
壁の穴があいとるはずじゃ。
There should be a bunch of holes
in the walls now.
そこを通っていけば
おるじゃろう。
Follow them to find him.
オーライ　俺は　ブラザーを探して
穴を通～らい。
All right, will do…
I'll look for Bro beyond
the walls I go through.
しっかりしろ　ブラザー！
今日から雷影は　ブラザー！
Hang in there, Bro.
From today,
you're the Raikage, y'know.
わかっている。
I know that!
今は　戦争中だ。
We're in the middle of a war!
俺が雷影として
里と国を守り抜く。
As the Raikage,
I will protect this village and
this nation to the very end!
それが親父の意志だ！
That is what my old man wanted!
ビー　お前は今日より雲雷峡に入り
尾獣玉の訓練をしろ。
Bee! Starting today, you will go
to Unraikyo, the Storm Cloud Ravine,
to work on
your Tailed Beast Bomb.
You will not be engaging
the enemy.
お前を敵には接触させん！
俺のラリアットは…。
But my Lariat…
I don't need your Lariat anymore!
お前のラリアットは　もういい！
敵が攻め入ってきたときは
里から出ず→
If the enemy attacks the village,
you will stay and
遠距離用の尾獣玉を使って
蹴散らせ！
take them out with
your long-range Tailed Beast Bomb!
(いいか！　お前は
二度と里から出るな！))
Remember! You are never to go
outside the village ever again!
ビー　お前もナルトも大切な人柱力だ。
Bee, you and Naruto
are precious Jinchuriki!
里と国にとって特別な存在。
You are special to
your villages and nations.
だからこそ行かせんと
言っているのだ！
That's why I'm saying you cannot go!
いくら強い人柱力といえど→
No matter how powerful
a Jinchuriki is,
他の人柱力は　すべて　暁…
敵によってやられ→
the others have been captured
by the Akatsuki and sealed.
封印されたのだぞ！
俺もナルトも負けやしねえ　自信！
We ain't gonna lose,
Naruto and me.
それがわかってる　俺たち自身！
That I can personally guarantee.
よかろう　試してみろ！
Fine, let's put it to the test!
ワシのラリアットと　どちらが上か！
My Lariat against yours!
We'll see who's stronger!
((ビー　まだまだ俺の理想とする
ダブル　ラリアットになってない。
Bee, we still have
a long way to go
before the Double Lariat is ideal.
今は俺が　お前の力に
合わせてるだけだ。
Right now, I'm toning down
my power to match yours.
もっと力をつけろよ！
You have to become stronger!
いつか　ブラザーを追い抜く！
その立場で　ぬくぬく！
I'll surpass you some day, you'll see.
On that day, I'll be carefree.
俺にとっては　それが理想！
That sounds ideal to me.
Talking down to you is my fantasy.
(上から目線で
ブラザーに説教を妄想！))
すげえ！
W-Wow…!
俺もナルトも人柱力だけが
力じゃねえからだ。
See, with Naruto and me…
it ain't just the power
of the Jinchuriki.
もっと強え力になる
もとが入ってる　この体。
We have something
stronger fundamentally.
八尾をもらう前に
ブラザーからもらった→
Your words to me, and me alone,
俺　個人として捨てられねえ言葉。
before I became the Eight Tails…
それさえあれば強くいられると
信じられる　殊の外。
They'll keep me strong,
no matter what,
even when all else fails.
((何かだ　それさえ見つかれば
強くいられる気がする。
Just "something"!
If I'm able to find it, I feel as though
I can stay strong.
(ビーには　それを見つけさせてやれ))
Let Bee find that something.
そうか！
I see…
((お前は俺にとって
特別な存在だ。
You are special to me!
(俺たちは最強のタッグだ！))
We are the ultimate tag team!
あのとき　真実の滝の前で言った
あの言葉が…。
What I said that day…
at the Waterfall of Truth…?
やっと気づいたか
バカ野郎　この野郎！
So you finally understand,
fool, ya fool!
上から目線で　ブラザーに説教！
Preaching at you from above
is my fantasy.
妄想じゃなくなったな　ア　イエー。
The fantasy is now a reality, oh yeah!
《チャクラまで真似る
白ゼツという敵の変化の術》
The enemy known as White Zetsu
uses a Transformation Jutsu
that can even mimic chakra…
Is there a way to see through
such a jutsu?
《本当にそんな術を
見抜く方法が…》
（シカク）ああ…　この資料でもない。
Nothing in these papers either.
（カツユ）雷影様と綱手様に→
Shouldn't we inform Lord Raikage
and Lady Hokage
この事態を伝えたほうが
よいのでは？
about this situation?
いや　ここを任された以上
この件は　こっちで処理する。
No… We were put in charge here,
so we'll deal with it.
２人には　ナルトとビー殿を
止めてもらうことに→
Besides, we want them
to concentrate
on stopping Naruto and Bee.
専念してもらいたいからな。
それがですね
綱手様はもう…。
Well, about that…
Lady Tsunade has already…
I'm looking through
new information right now!
今　新しい資料を見てる。
早く解決策を
立案しなけりゃならん。
It's imperative that we find
a solution right away!
Please! Let me focus.
集中させてくれ。
You are very special to me…
お前は俺にとって
特別な存在…。
I do not deny that I said,
"We are the ultimate tag team."
俺たちは最強のタッグだと
確かに　そう言った。
That's it?
あれだけ…
たったあれだけの言葉で→
Just those words are enough
to keep you strong?
強くいられるというのか？
里や国にとっての
俺だけじゃねえ。
I don't just live and fight
for the village and nation.
ブラザーにとっての俺だ。
I live and fight for you too, Bro!
だが　ブラザーは
俺を守ろうとするあまりの気遣い。
Still you're way
too overprotective, Bro.
俺の力を信じなくなっていった
毎回。
And you're losing faith
in my strength, y'know.
人柱力になれば
いろいろなもんなくして→
You lose a lot as a Jinchuriki…
I tell ya, the heart grows empty.
心　ガリガリ。
But it made me see what's dear to hold
and now my heart is made of gold
でも　だからこそ
なくしたくないもんが→
光って見えてくる　心　ピカピカ。
尾獣だけが
力のもとじゃねえ　オーケー？
Tailed Beast power isn't
my foundation! Okay?!
Before the Tailed Beast
became my mate,
尾獣が入る前に入ってたもんが
光りだしたら→
something inside me
had started to illuminate.
太陽ぐらいでかかったと
気づく大事。
I saw that it was
as big as the sun.
And that's my true power,
it's the one.
それこそが力のもとだと
気づく大筋。
That's why I can keep
the Eight Tails reined in.
だからこそ俺は　八尾を唯一
コントロールできたと　確信。
Naruto has the same sun deep within.
ナルトの中にも
その太陽がある各人。
And he has two of 'em, it's amazing.
Talk about a new innovation.
しかも　それが
２つもあるのが革新！
そうだな。
You're right…
It really is like the sun.
確かに
太陽みたいなもんかもしんねえ。
Naruto Uzumaki,
what are your two suns?
うずまきナルト。
お前のその２つの太陽とは
何だ？
父ちゃんと　母ちゃんだ！
My mom and dad!
父と母。
Your mother and father?
四代目火影と
うずまきクシナか？
The Fourth Hokage and
Kushina Uzumaki?
しかし　お前が生まれてすぐに
２人は死んだはずだ。
But both of them died right
after you were born.
《九尾チャクラのコントロール修業のとき
何かあったな。
He must have
experienced something
while training to control
the Nine Tails' chakra.
ナルトがペイン戦で
九尾化しかけたときも→
During Naruto's battle with Pain,
he started transforming
into Nine Tails.
封印の術式に仕掛けを
ほどこしていたミナトが出てきて→
Naruto mentioned
that Minato appeared
and had put his essence
into the seal's formula
自分を助けたと言っていたな。
to stop the transformation.
I knew he wouldn't go down
without a fight!
ただでは死なん男だとは
思ったが》
When I was trying to
control Nine Tails' power…
この九尾の力を手に入れるとき→
Dad made sure to let me
meet my mom.
父ちゃんは　ちゃんと
母ちゃんに会わせてくれた。
He wove her chakra into the seal,
九尾の封印を開くと→
母ちゃんが
俺に会いに来るよう→
so that if the Nine Tails' seal
was undone,
チャクラを仕込んどいて
くれたんだってばよ。
Mom would come and see me.
俺のために。
He did it all for me!
《うずまき一族特有の→
The Fourth Hokage studied
the unique Sealing Jutsu
of the Uzumaki Clan…
封印術を教わっていた
四代目火影。
And Kushina's chakra and
life force were powerful…
それに
クシナのあの強いチャクラと生命力。
It's possible.
あながち嘘でもなかろう》
《やはりな》
Just as I thought.
この力をくれたとき
母ちゃんが全部教えてくれた。
When she gave me this power,
Mom told me everything.
父ちゃんは　昔一度→
That long ago, Dad fought with
the same guy with the mask…
面の男とやりあってて→
And he learned two things…
そんで　そのとき
確信したことが２つあるって。
１つは　その面の男が
この先→
One was that this masked guy
would try to destroy the future.
必ず災いをもたらすって
言ってた。
そんで２つ目は→
And the other was that…
The only one who could stop him
それを止めるのが
人柱力として→
was the Jinchuriki who controlled
the Nine Tails… Me!
九尾の力をコントロールした
俺なんだって。
《面をした男　マダラのことか。
A masked man…
Was it Madara?
やはり　あの木ノ葉九尾事件は
マダラの仕業だったのか》
So Madara caused that Nine Tails'
incident in the Hidden Leaf?
《ミナトが　ナルトに九尾を封印し→
So the reason Minato sealed
the Nine Tails in Naruto,
その封印を開ける鍵まで
残したのは→
but left a key to unlock the seal…
was for this purpose?!
このためだったのか。
He never did anything that
was unnecessary.
確かに　アイツは
ムダなことをしないヤツだった。
So he concluded that
this masked man, Madara,
つまり　それほど面の男。
マダラが強く　脅威であると
判断したんだ。
posed an enormous threat to us.
九尾の力を
コントロールした者でなければ→
And that only the one who controlled
the Nine Tails' power
had a chance of defeating him…
倒せるような敵ではないと。
だから　ナルトに》
So he chose Naruto…
So Minato entrusted everything
to you?
ミナトは　お前にすべてを
託したということか？
己が救世主ではなかったと。
He knew he wasn't the savior?
父ちゃんが　自分のことを→
I don't know if Dad
ever considered himself
救世主と思ってたか
どうかはわかんねえ。
to be a savior or not.
けど　俺の師匠は
父ちゃんを予言の子。
But my master told me that
Dad was the Child of Prophecy…
the savior.
救世主だって言った。
Do you recall what
I told you earlier?
さっき言ったことを
覚えているか？
That savior, Minato, is dead.
その救世主ミナトは死んだ。
Don't you think that was a failure?
これを失敗でなかったと
お前は言うのか？
確かに　父ちゃんは死んだ。
You're right. My dad died.
母ちゃんと一緒に。
He died along with my mom,
trying to protect Hidden Leaf Village
その敵と　九尾から
木ノ葉の里を守り抜いて→
from the enemy and the Nine Tails!
Trying to protect me!
俺を守り抜いて。
ほんの一瞬だったけど
そんときに　２人が俺にくれた→
It only lasted a moment…
But in that moment,
they gave me something.
すげぇいっぱいのもんが→
They gave me the belief that
やりきれるんだって
俺を信じさせてくれる。
I am capable of lots and
lots and lots of things!
救世主も　俺に託したんだ。
And they entrusted me to
be the savior of the world!
雷影！　ナルトを殺し　敵の目的を
先のばしすれば→
Raikage!
If you kill Naruto to try
to stall the enemy,
then this time for sure,
the Nine Tails will be taken!
今度は　必ず　九尾をとられるぞ！
And it will definitely spell
the end of the world!
それこそ　世界が終わる！
Only Naruto can control
the Nine Tails' power.
ナルトだから　九尾の力を
コントロールできたんだ。
ミナトが　そう信じたとおり
ナルトを行かせることが→
Just as Minato believed!
Letting Naruto go is the way to
protect shinobi, and everyone!
忍を　みんなを守ることになる。
私は　ナルトにかける！
My bet is on Naruto!
お前の判断は？
So what is your decision?!
Let me go too, fool, ya fool!
俺もだぜ！　バカ野郎　この野郎！
俺は　ブラザーの言うとおり大バカだ！
やっぱり。
Like you always said,
I'm a big fool too.
そんで　ここにいるナルトも
大バカで間違いない。　厄介！
And Naruto here is just like me…
Don't you agree?
けど　事を成し遂げるのは→
But to succeed, you need
fools like us
who don't care at all
how big or strong the wall!
壁の強さと　大きさをかえりみない
大バカで　間違いない！
Yahoo!
ヤッホー！
あれは　マックス状態。
Bro's at top speed,
you can't go much faster!
I think he wants to kill Naruto…
This can become a disaster!
ナルトを殺す気なのか？
不測の事態！
あいかわらずのきかん坊だ！
As always, you're so stubborn.
I have no choice, but to join in!
今度は　私も参戦する！
《バアちゃんを
巻き込むわけにはいかねえ！》
I can't involve Granny in this!
いくぞ　ナルト！
Here I come, Naruto!
俺ってば　いろいろ
託されてるもんがあっから。
A lot of people have
put their trust in me.
失敗はしねえ！
I won't fail!
((ミナト：俺も　いろいろ
背負ってるものがあるから→
I shoulder many responsibilities too.
(失敗はしないよ))
I won't fail!
He dodged it?!
《かわした？　バカ野郎　この野郎！
これじゃ本当に…》
Fool, ya fool! He really is…
《まるで　黄色い閃光！》
…just like the Yellow Flash!
雷影のおっちゃんの言うとおり→
You're right, Raikage…
失敗したら
救世主じゃなくなっちまう。
If I fail, I'm not a savior.
だから　絶対　失敗しねえ！
So I will not fail!
Just like my dad didn't.
父ちゃんがそうしたように…。
救世主の父ちゃんから
学んだように。
Just like my savior dad taught me!
フンッ！　わしなりに
確かめたくてな。
I just wanted to see for myself…
So I came at you,
with intent to kill.
殺す気で攻撃した。
このわしの最速パンチをかわしたのは
お前で　２人目だ。
You're only the second one
to ever outrun my fastest punch.
どうやら
救世主は生きているようだ。
It seems the savior is alive…
within you.
お前の中で。
行って来い！
Now go.
おうっ！
Right!
（シカク）やはり　これしかない。
This is the only way.
この資料によれば
九尾チャクラモード時のナルトは→
According to this data, when Naruto is
in Nine Tails' chakra mode,
he can sense the enemy's hostility.
敵の悪意を感知できるとある。
これなら　白いヤツの変化の術も
見抜けるはずだ。
He'll be able to see through
the white being's Transformation Jutsu.
それに　影分身の使えるナルトなら→
Furthermore, we can deploy
Naruto's shadow clones
各戦場へ出向き
これを処理できる。
to each battlefield to counter them.
これ以上　時間が経てば
もう取り返しのつかぬ状態になる。
If we delay any longer,
there will be no turning back!
だが　問題は…。
The only problem is…
（マブイ）人柱力であるナルト君を
守るための戦争に→
This is a war to protect Naruto,
a Jinchuriki.
ナルト君を投入するなんて…。
Throwing into him into battle
それでは　本末転倒ですよ。
would be like getting
our priorities backwards.
そもそも　雷影様が　そんなことを
許すとは　到底　思えません。
In the first place,
Lord Raikage w
だよな…。
あの～　それが
そうでもないみたいでして…。
（マダラ）長かった夜も明ける。
こいつらの目も
そろそろ　なじむ頃だな。
人柱力を使った　新たなペイン六道。
少し　俺好みに変えてはいるがな。
♪～
＜　きょうから１０代目＞
＜旬の魚が大好きな豆助＞
♪～
豆助　きょうの　お魚は
今が旬のアレよ
＜　その魚とは？＞
＜　それは…＞